CURRICULUM VITAE

Sarath Sasi P

Al Warqa 1 Dubai, UAE 00971 50 472 5685 sarathss2009@gmail.com

Summary

Proficient and highly knowledgeable Sales Engineer with computer science education and 4 year track record of sales success. Motivated professional who excels at delivering quality service while exceeding revenue benchmarks on a consistent basis.

Right now looking for a suitable position with a company where outstanding performance is recognised and work on a variety of high profile project. Willing to take ownership of core components.

Skill Highlights

- Top-ranked sales manager
- Excellent closing techniques
- Strong prospector
- Contract negotiation
- Adept multi-tasker
- Lead generation
- Consultative sales techniques
- Account management
- Motivational and engaging style
- Analytical problem solver

Experience

August 2016 - Present

Advanced Fiberglass Industry. Ajman, UAE Senior Sales Manager

- Optimize revenue streams by networking for additional business prospects with established clients.
- Plan strategic brand-building events to expand product portfolio.
- Identify coordinate and participate in client relationship-building activities and meetings.
- Cultivate relationships with key players to create beneficial referral systems.

- Answer customer questions regarding products prices and availability.
- Providing sales support during virtual and onsite client meetings.
- Liaising with both current and potential clients to develop existing and new business opportunities.
- Identifying the customer's current and future requirements.
- Identifying client requirements.
- Reviewing consultant drawings, plans and other documents in order to prepare detailed technical proposal for them.
- Preparing reports for head office and senior managers.
- Offering after-sales support services.
- Conveying solution benefits to both business and technical audiences.
- Defining products, services and solutions to potential clients.
- Preparing and presenting potential cost benefit analysis to potential clients.
- Delivering presentations and demos to team members.
- Negotiating tender, contract terms and conditions.

January 2015 - July 2016

SEBS TECHNOLOGIES.

AJMAN, UAE

Sales Executive

- Generating leads from customer referrals.
- Dialling upwards of 100 cold calls every day.
- Provide customers with both pre-sale and post-sale technical engineering and implementation support.
- Presenting technical and sales information to small and large audiences.
- Generating sales leads through building up professional contacts and networking.
- Co-ordinating sales projects.
- Being a technical and sales point of contact for prospective customers.
- Preparing weekly sales plans.
- Establishing a favourable climate with customers.
- Capturing data and getting feedback from customers.
- Holding face to face meetings with customers.
- Creating invoices for sales.
- Performing other related duties as required and assigned.

Academic Qualification

B.E Computer Science & Engineering - Hindusthan College of Engineering & Technology

(ANNA UNIVERSITY, COIMBATORE-INDIA)

2010 - 2014

Govt Model Boys Higher Secondary School, Thrissur - India 2008 - 2010

J.P.E.H.S School Koorkenchery, Thrissur - India 2008

Personal Details

Name: Sarath Sasi P

Gender: Male
Religion: Hindu
Marital Status: Single

Date of Birth: 20th Nov 1991

Languages: English, Hindi, Malayalam, Tamil

Nationality: Indian

UAE Address: Al Warqa 1, Dubai Visa Status: Employment Visa

Passport No: H1962260
Date of expiry: 31 Dec 2018
Place of Issue: Cochin
UAE Driving Licence No: 168173

^{*}References and certificates furnished promptly upon request.